# **Aaron Apple**

303 Ilchester Avenue – Baltimore MD, 21218 (847) 970-0924 • apple@cogsci.jhu.edu • aaronapple.github.io/

#### **Profile**

Recent graduate of the Department of Cognitive Science at Johns Hopkins University, with expertise in human development and linguistics, data analysis, and visualization, with 4+ years of experience in research coordination, looking to apply my diverse research skills to problems in the applied social sciences.

### **Education**

**Johns Hopkins University** 

Baltimore, MD

Masters of Arts in Cognitive Science.

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2016

Advisors: Drs. Akira Omaki, Kyle Rawlins & Geraldine Legendre

Chicago, IL

**Linguistics Society of America**Graduate of the 2015 LSA Summer Institute at the University of Chicago

Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2015

New York University

New York, NY

Bachelors of Arts in Language and Mind, Minor in Creative Writing

Aug. 2008 - Dec. 2012

## **Skills**

Research: Experimental design; Scientific writing; Data visualization; Public speaking; Grant editing; Data management; Research coordination

Programming languages: R; Python; MATLAB

**Software**: Microsoft Office; Adobe Creative Cloud; SPSS; Tableau; FileMaker Pro; Audacity; SR Research Experiment Builder & Data Viewer

**Statistical & Experimental Methods**: ANOVA; Mixed-effects regression; Bayesian inference; Neural networks; Question answering; Preferential looking; Visual-world eye-tracking; Eye-tracking during reading; Self-paced reading **Languages**: English (native); French (proficient)

## **Professional Experience**

#### Manager of the Language Processing and Development Lab

Baltimore, MD

PI: Dr. Akira Omaki, Department of Cognitive Science, The Johns Hopkins University.

Jan. 2013 - Jul. 2015

- o Developed pipelines to manage, analyze, and visualize data for 12 experiments.
- Designed two experiments on child and adult language processing.
- Wrote five articles submitted to peer-reviewed journals.
- Presented my findings at two conferences.
- Edited NSF grant application for a project on child sentence processing and executive control.
- Supervised five research assistants on four research projects.
- Conducted literature reviews for 7 experiments.
- Wrote, designed, and edited newsletter presenting findings from 8 experiments for laypeople.

## Research Assistant in the Davachi Memory Lab

PI: Dr. Lila Davachi, Department of Psychology, New York University.

May 2012 - Dec. 2012

- Assisted in designing and coding MEG experiment on memory reactivation.
- Managed participant recruitment and data collection for two fMRI experiments.

#### Research Assistant in the Consciousness and Computation Lab

New York, NY

New York, NY

PI: Dr. Hakwan Lau, Department of Psychology, Columbia University.

May 2012 - Dec. 2012

o Designed and coded behavioral experiment on dynamic control of memory and attention.

• Managed participant recruitment and data collection for three behavioral experiments.

#### Research Assistant in the Neurolinguistics Lab

New York, NY

PI: Dr. Liina Pylkkänen, Department of Linguistics, New York University.

Sept. 2011 - April 2012

 $\circ~$  Designed and coded MEG experiment on domain generality of semantic processing.

#### **Editorial Intern at DVL Seigenthaler PR**

Chicago, IL

• Wrote twelve press releases for three business clients.

Aug. 2010 - Dec. 2010

o Copy edited press releases and outreach magazines for two philanthropic clients.

#### Intern at 826CHI

Chicago, IL

• Administrated the after-school tutoring program of 30 children and tutors.

Aug. 2010 - Dec. 2010

o Taught writing as a teaching assistant in two English classes in a Chicago public high school.

## **Publications, Presentations and Awards**

Atkinson, E., **Apple**, **A.**, Omaki, A. (2016). Similarity of Wh-Phrases and Acceptability Variation in Wh-Islands. *Frontiers in Psychology*, 6.

Omaki, A, Lau, E. F., Davidson White, I., Dakan, M., **Apple, A.**, & Phillips, C. (2015). Hyper-active gap filling. *Frontiers in Psychology*, 6.

**Apple, A.** & Omaki, A. (2015). Incrementality and garden-path recovery in children's resolution of direct object vs. sentential complement ambiguity. Paper presented at the *Boston University Conference on Language Development, November 13*, 2015.

**Apple, A.** & Omaki, A. (2015). Development of sentential complement ambiguity processing. Poster presented at the *CUNY 2015 Conference on Sentence Processing, March 21*.

Omaki, A. & **Apple, A.** (2014). Adaptation of active gap filling in coordinated sentences. Talk presented at the *AMLaP* 2014, *September 4*.

**Apple, A.**, Bemis, D., Marcus, G., Pylkkänen, L. (2012). Domain General Compositional Processing: An MEG Study. *Dean's Undergraduate Research Fund*, NYU. Poster presented at the Dean's Undergraduate Research conference and grant recipient of the highest award, \$1000.

Apple, A., Omaki, A. (In preparation). The role of incremental parsing on Japanese infants' word learning.

Apple, A., Omaki, A. (In preparation). Japanese infants' abstract knowledge of word order.

**Apple, A.**, Omaki, A. (In preparation). Filler-gap processing in coordinate structures.

**Apple, A.**, Omaki, A. (In preparation). Incrementality and garden-path recovery in child resolution of complement ambiguity.

## **Volunteering**

#### **Harwood Community Association**

Baltimore, MD

Volunteer and organizer

Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Harwood's 2016 National Night Out Against Crime: Solicited food donations from local businesses, ran the BBQ grill, and assisted in managing other volunteers.
- The 2015 Ilchester Back to School Block Party: Solicited school supplies donations from local businesses and assisted in managing other volunteers.